A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, 1953-2004
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services 1953-2004
The Library of Virginia
43927
112 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Records, Commissioner's Office, 102 Governor Street, Richmond, VA 23219, transferred 14 August 2008 and accessioned 18 August 2008.
Biographical/Historical Information
On 29 March 29 1877, the General Assembly passed an act creating the Department of Agriculture, Mining, and Manufacturing to compile a geological handbook, analyze soils and fertilizers, dispense information to agriculturists in the state, and distribute seeds provided by the federal government. The Board of Agriculture was established by the General Assembly on March 5, 1888, to manage the department. The name of the department was changed to the Department of Agriculture and Immigration by an act passed on 25 February 25 1908, and the agency was given the additional mission of promoting the immigration of farmers into the state. On 27 March 1914, the General Assembly made the commissioner of the department a member of the Convict Lime Grinding Board. This board, which supervised the employment of state penitentiary convicts at state lime grinding plants, was abolished by the state government reorganization act passed by the General Assembly on 18 April 1927, and its duties were transferred to the Board of Agriculture and Immigration.
A major shift in focus occurred when, in a statewide referendum held on 1 November 1966, the voters approved a proposed constitutional amendment passed by the General Assembly on March 11 that changed the name of the department to the Department of Agriculture and Commerce. The governor issued a proclamation of the name change on 30 November 1966, and on 4 March 1971, the General Assembly passed an act codifying the change. The name of the department was changed to the Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services by an act passed by the General Assembly on 24 March 1978.
Past Commissioners include: S. Mason Carbaugh, 1972-1991; Clinton V. Turner, 1991-1994; and J. Carlton Courter, III, 1994-2006.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Records, are housed in 112 boxes. This collection has been processed using minimal processing standards: the original arrangement has been maintained, the container list is brief and simple, and the records have not been refoldered and fasteners have not been removed. The collection is arranged into five series. Series have been designated for: I. Commissioners's Correspondence, 1982-2004 (bulk 1995-2003); II. Commissioners's Correspondence and Subject Files, 1995-2003; III. Board Correspondence and Minutes, 1958-1998; IV. Commissioner's Speeches and Correspondence, 1968-1998; and V. Special Interest Items, 1953-2001. These records include: agendas, agreements, correspondence, memorandums, meeting notes, minutes, legislative files, budget materials, speeches, and reports.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Commissioner's Correspondence, 1982-2004 (bulk 1995-2003)
II. Commissioner's Correspondence and Subject Files, 1995-2003
III. Board Correspondence and Minutes, 1958-1998
IV. Commissioner's Speeches and Correspondence, 1968-1998
V. Special Interest Items, 1953-2001
Contents List
- I. Commissioner's Correspondence, 1982-2004 (bulk 1995-2003)., Extent: 60 cubic feet (60 boxes). (Box 1-60)
  This series is arranged chronologically, followed by miscellaneous materials and documents the correspondence sent and received by the Commissioner's Office Notable subjects and correspondence include: J. Carlton Courter, III, Office of the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, Agricultural Leadership Group Meetings, 1998-1999, National Association of State Departments of Agriculture (NASDA), Southern Association of State Departments of Agriculture (SASDA), Southern United States Trade Association (SUSTA), Craig M. Halbleib, Donald G. Blankenship, Donald W. Butts, Eastern Shore Vegetable and Shellfish Advisory Commmittee, and the budget. The series consists of agendas, agreements, budgets, correspondence, form letters, handouts, legislation, memorandum, meeting notes, notes, presentations, and reports.
  - 1995
    - Commodity Services (Box 1)
    - Acquaculture (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Marketing (part one) (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Marketing (part two) (Box 1)
    - Ward, Ralph C. (part one) (Box 1)
    - Ward, Ralph C. (part two) (Box 1)
    - Weights and Measures (Box 1)
    - Marvin Lawson - Pesticide Management (Box 1)
    - Pesticides (Box 1)
    - Gypsy Moth (Box 1)
    - Ginseng (Box 1)
    - Endangered Species (Box 1)
    - Pair Re-organization (Box 1)
    - Suggested Response to Secretary's Office (part one) (Box 1)
    - Suggested Response to Secretary's Office (part two) (Box 1)
    - Suggested Response to Secretary's Office (part three) (Box 1)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#2) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#3) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#4) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#5) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#6) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#7) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#8) (Box 2)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#1) (Box 3)
    - Hazelwood, Moyer W. (Box 3)
    - Memos to SMT (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous - Commissioner's Office (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous - Agricultural Economic Development Service Unit (Box 3)
    - Dickinson, William P. (#1) (Box 3)
    - Dickinson, William P. (#2) (Box 3)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (#1) (Box 3)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (#2) (Box 3)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (#3) (Box 3)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#14) (Box 4)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#15) (Box 4)
    - Morgan, B. Gayle (Box 4)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#1) (Box 4)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#2) (Box 4)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#3) (Box 4)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#4) (Box 4)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#5) (Box 4)
    - Weekly Reports from Secretary's Office (Box 4)
    - Weekly Reports to Secretary's Office (Box 4)
    - Radler, Tonl L. (Box 5)
    - Pugh, Sarah D. (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Planning, Policy and Agricultural Development (Box 5)
    - Seward, Roy E. (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous - Human Resource Office (Box 5)
    - Smith, Harriet G. (Box 5)
    - Jackson, Karen E. (Box 5)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#9) (Box 5)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#10) (Box 5)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#11) (Box 5)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#12) (Box 5)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#13) (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous - Dairy and Foods Division (Box 6)
    - Tubbs, Mark D. (Box 6)
    - Consumer Affairs Toll Free Line (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Consumer Affairs (Box 6)
    - SulzBach, Betty W. (Box 6)
    - Avian Influenza (Box 6)
    - Animal Health Laboratory System (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Animal Health Division (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Animal Industry Services Division (Box 6)
    - Sims, William D. (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Finance Office (Box 6)
    - Palmer, Terri A. (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Purchasing (Box 6)
    - Martin, Teddy R. (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Facilities Management (Box 6)
    - Garey, Louis M. (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Information Systems (Box 6)
    - Allgeier, Jerry P. (Box 6)
    - Halbleib, M. Craig (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Administration (Box 6)
    - Layne, Ronald K. (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous - Communication and Media Relations (Box 6)
  - 1996
    - 1996 Legislative Guidelines (Box 7)
    - 1996 General Assembly Session (Box 7)
    - House Agriculture Committee, Public Hearing, VDACS, 11 January 1996 (Box 7)
    - Presentation for the Commerce and Trade Sub-Committee of the House Appropriations Committee, 25 January 1996 (Box 7)
    - 1996 Legislation (Box 7)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (Box 7)
    - Board of Agriculture and Consumer Services Meeting, Tour, 21-23 July 1996 (Box 7)
    - Eggborn, Phil - Plant and Pest Services (Box 7)
    - Rogers, Alan - Product and Industry Standards (Box 7)
    - Lawson, Marvin - Pesticide Service (Box 7)
    - Pesticides (Box 7)
    - Meat and Poultry Inspection (Box 7)
    - Gypsy Moth (Box 7)
    - Endangered Species (Box 7)
    - Dairy Services - On Call Policy (Box 7)
    - Office of Dairy and Foods (Box 7)
    - Privacy Guard (CUC) (Box 7)
    - Office of Consumer Affairs - Staffing Proposal (Box 7)
    - Office of Consumer Affairs (Box 7)
    - Division of Consumer Protection (Box 8)
    - Butts, Donald (#1) (Box 8)
    - Butts, Donald (#2) (Box 8)
    - Avian Influenza (Box 8)
    - Animal Health Lab System (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Animal Industry Services (Box 8)
    - Sims, William D. (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Finance Office (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Purchasing (Box 8)
    - Martin, Teddy R. (Box 8)
    - Garey, Louis M. (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Information Systems (Box 8)
    - Allgeier, Jerry P. (Box 8)
    - Halbleib, M. Craig (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Administrative and Financial Services (Box 8)
    - Layne, Ronald K. (Box 8)
    - Lidholm, Elaine (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Communication and Media Relations (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Planning (Box 8)
    - Morgan, B. Gayle (Box 9)
    - Courter, James C., III (#1) (Box 9)
    - Courter, James C., III (#2) (Box 9)
    - Courter, James C., III (#3) (Box 9)
    - Courter, James C., III (#4) (Box 9)
    - Courter, James C., III (#5) (Box 9)
    - Courter, James C., III (#6) (Box 9)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#1) (Box 10)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#2) (Box 10)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#3) (Box 10)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#4) (Box 10)
    - Weekly Reports from Secretary (Box 10)
    - Weekly Reports to Secretary (Box 10)
    - Ward, Ralph C. (#1) (Box 10)
    - Ward, Ralph C. (#2) (Box 10)
    - Seed Laboratory (Box 10)
    - Seed Lab Privatization Study (Box 10)
    - Meat and Poultry Services (Box 10)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (#2) (Box 11)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (#1) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#7) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#8) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#9) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#10) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#11) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#12) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#13) (Box 11)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (#14) (Box 11)
    - Suggested Response (#1) (Box 12)
    - Suggested Response (#2) (Box 12)
    - Pugh, Sarah D. (Box 12)
    - Seward, Roy D. (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous - Human Resource Office (Box 12)
    - Smith, Harriet G. (Box 12)
    - Jackson, Karen E. (Box 12)
    - Hazelwood, Moyer W. (Box 12)
    - Memos to SMT (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous - Commissioner's Office (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous - Ag. Dev. Services Unit (Box 12)
    - Dickinson, William P. (Box 12)
  - 1997
    - Bob Colvin - Office of Con. Affairs (#2) (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Consumer Protection (#1) (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Consumer Protection (#2) (Box 13)
    - Butts, Donald W. (#1) (Box 13)
    - Butts, Donald W. (#2) (Box 13)
    - Veterinary Series Compensation Study (Box 13)
    - Avian Influenza (Box 13)
    - Animal Health Lab System (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Animal Industry Services (Box 13)
    - Sims, William D. (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Finance Office (Box 13)
    - Adams, Sandy (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Purchasing (Box 13)
    - Martin, Teddy R. (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Facilities Management (Box 13)
    - Garey, Louis M. (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Information Systems (Box 13)
    - Allgeier, Jerry P. (Box 13)
    - Halbleib, Craig M. (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Administrative and Financial Services (Box 13)
    - Layne, Ronald K. (Box 13)
    - Communication Office (Box 13)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#7) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#8) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#9) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#10) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#11) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#12) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#13) (Box 14)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III. (#14) (Box 14)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#1) (Box 14)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#2) (Box 15)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#3) (Box 15)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#4) (Box 15)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (#5) (Box 15)
    - Weekly Reports from Secretary (Box 15)
    - Weekly Reports to Secretary (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Marketing (#1) (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Marketing (#2) (Box 15)
    - Seed Laboratory (Box 15)
    - Eggborn, Phil - Plant and Pest Serv. (Box 15)
    - Rogers, Alan - Product and Industry (Box 15)
    - Lawson, Marvin - Pesticide Serv. (Box 15)
    - Pesticides (Box 15)
    - Meat and Poultry Inspection (Box 15)
    - Gypsy Moth (Box 15)
    - Endangered Species (Box 15)
    - Office of Dairy and Foods (Box 15)
    - Consumer Affairs Report to General Assembly (Box 15)
    - Colvin, Bob - Office of Consumer Affairs (Box 15)
    - Consumer Affairs Activities of VDACS for 1997 - Report to the General Assembly (Box 15)
    - Ward, Ralph C. (Box 16)
    - Commodity Services (Box 16)
    - Equine (Box 16)
    - Equine Position (Box 16)
    - Office of International Marketing (Box 16)
    - Accomplishments - VDACS (Box 16)
    - Dept. of Accounts (Box 16)
    - Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations (Box 16)
    - Agriculture in the Classroom (Box 16)
    - Agriculture 2000 Transition Task Force (Box 16)
    - Agenda, SMT (Box 16)
    - AG News Release (Box 16)
    - Aging, Department for the (Box 16)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. (Box 16)
    - Apple Board, Virginia (Box 16)
    - Apples - Mexico (Box 16)
    - Aquaculture (Box 16)
    - Atlantic Rural Exposition (Box 16)
    - Attorney General's Office (Box 16)
    - Audits - VDACS (Box 16)
    - Auditor of Public Accounts (Box 16)
    - Internal Auditor, Dept. of (Box 16)
    - Awards Committee - VDACS (Box 16)
    - Boll Weevil (Box 16)
    - Boll Weevil - Southeast Program (Box 16)
    - Cattlemen's Association (Box 16)
    - Century Farm (Box 16)
    - Chamber of Commerce (Box 16)
    - Virginia Code Commission (Box 16)
    - Combined Virginia Campaign (CVC) (Box 16)
    - Commission on Local Government (Box 16)
    - Commodity (Box 16)
    - Commonwealth Competition Council (Box 16)
    - Commonwealth Management Institute (Box 16)
    - Comptroller's Office (Box 16)
    - Conflict of Interest (Box 16)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of (Box 16)
    - Consolidated Lab Services, Dept. of (Box 16)
    - Consumer Affairs Adv. Comm. (Box 16)
    - Crop Insurance (Box 16)
    - Dairy Compact - Southern (Box 16)
    - Dairymen's Association, Virginia State (Box 16)
    - Deaf and Hard of Hearing, Dept. (Box 16)
    - Delegates (Box 16)
    - Delmarva Poultry (Box 16)
    - Disasters (Box 16)
    - Downsizing (Box 16)
    - Eastern Shore Farmers Market (Box 16)
    - Eastern Shore Marketing Cooperative (Box 16)
    - Eastern Shore Vegetable and Shellfish Grower Advisory Committee (Box 16)
    - E-Coli (Box 17)
    - Education, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Egg Council (Box 17)
    - Egg Law Proposals - Virginia (Box 17)
    - Egg Quality Insurance Program - Virginia (Box 17)
    - Emergency Services, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Emergency Services Task Force (Box 17)
    - Employee Relations Counselors, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Environmental Protection Agency (US) (Box 17)
    - Environmental Quality, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Equal Opportunity Plan (Box 17)
    - Virginia Farm Bureau Federation (Box 17)
    - On Farm Sales Study SR29 (Box 17)
    - Fee Revenue - Feed, Seed, Fertilizer and Lime Programs (Box 17)
    - Feed - Ruminant (Box 17)
    - Food and Drug Administration (Box 17)
    - Forestry, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) (Box 17)
    - Friends of the Industry of Agriculture (Box 17)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - 1997 General Assembly (Box 17)
    - 1997 General Assembly Instructions and Guidelines (Box 17)
    - General Services, Dept. of (Box 17)
    - Virginia Executive Institute (Box 17)
    - Virginia Horse Industry Board (Box 17)
    - VPI and SU (Box 17)
    - Volunteerism, Office of (Box 17)
    - Workforce Development Initiatives (Box 17)
    - WTA Review (Box 17)
    - Virginia Agribusiness Council (Box 17)
    - Virginia Agricultural Council (Box 17)
    - Virginia Board of Agriculture and Consumer Services (Box 17)
    - Virginia Cattle Industry Board (Box 17)
    - Virginia Farmers Market Board (Box 17)
    - Virginia Marine Products Board (Box 17)
    - NASDA (#2) (Box 17)
    - NASDA (#1) (Box 17)
    - Courter, James C., III (1) (Box 18)
    - Courter, James C., III (2) (Box 18)
    - Courter, James C., III (3) (Box 18)
    - Courter, James C., III (4) (Box 18)
    - Courter, James C., III (5) (Box 18)
    - Courter, James C., III (6) (Box 18)
    - Suggested Responses (1) (Box 18)
    - Suggested Responses (2) (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Communications and Media Relations (Box 19)
    - Hockman, Jeb (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous - Agriculture Stewardship (Box 19)
    - Pubh, Sarah D. (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Policy, Planning and Research (1) (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Policy, Planning and Research (2) (Box 19)
    - Seward, Roy E. (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous - Human Resource Office (Box 19)
    - Smith, Harriet G. (Box 19)
    - Jackson, Karen E. (Box 19)
    - Kapelewski, Joe (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous - AG Dev. Services Unit (Box 19)
    - Dickinson, William P., Jr. (Box 19)
    - Memos to SMT (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous - Commissioner's Office (Box 19)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (1) (Box 19)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (2) (Box 19)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (3) (Box 19)
  - 1998
    - Halbleib, Craig M. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Administrative and Financial Services (Box 20)
    - Layne, Ronald K. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Communication and Media Relations (Box 20)
    - Lidholm, Elaine J. (Box 20)
    - Agricultural Stewardship Act (Box 20)
    - Pugh, Sarah (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous - Office of Policy, Planning and Research (Box 20)
    - Seward, Roy E. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous - Human Resource Office (Box 20)
    - Smith, Harriet (Box 20)
    - Jackson, Karen E. (Box 20)
    - Authorization - Blankenship from Commissioner - Re: Travel (Box 20)
    - Kapelewski, Joe (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous - Ag. Dev. Services Unit (Box 20)
    - Dickinson, William P., Jr. (Box 20)
    - Memos to the SMT (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous - Commissioner's Office (Box 20)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (2) (Box 20)
    - Suggested Response (1) (Box 21)
    - Suggested Response (2) (Box 21)
    - Suggested Response (3) (Box 21)
    - Suggested Response (4) (Box 21)
    - Suggested Response (5) (Box 21)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (12) (Box 21)
    - Courter, J. Carlton (11) (Box 21)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (1) (Box 21)
    - Allgeier, Jerry P. (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous - Information Systems (Box 22)
    - Garey, Louis M. (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous - Facilities Management (empty) (Box 22)
    - Martin, Teddy R. (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous - Procurement (Box 22)
    - Adams, Sandy (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous - Finance Office (Box 22)
    - Sims, William D. (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous - Animal Industry Services (Box 22)
    - Animal Health Lab System (empty) (Box 22)
    - Avian Influenza (empty) (Box 22)
    - Veterinary Series Compensation Study (empty) (Box 22)
    - Butts, Donald W. (2) (Box 22)
    - Butts, Donald W. (1) (Box 22)
    - Meat and Poultry Services (Box 23)
    - Pesticides (Box 23)
    - Lawson, Marvin - Pesticide Services (Box 23)
    - Rogers, Alan (Box 23)
    - Eggborn, Phil - Plant and Pest Services (Box 23)
    - Seed Lab (Box 23)
    - Ivy, Joanne (Director of Marketing) (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Marketing (Box 23)
    - Commodity Services (Box 23)
    - Equine (Box 23)
    - Office of International Marketing (Box 23)
    - Bob Colvin - Office of Consumer Affairs (Box 23)
    - Consumer Affairs Activities Report (Box 23)
    - Office of Dairy and Foods (Box 23)
    - Endangered Species (Box 23)
    - Gypsy Moth (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Consumer Protection (2) (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous - Division of Consumer Protection (1) (Box 23)
    - Weekly Reports to the Secretary (Box 24)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (3) (Box 24)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (2) (Box 24)
    - Secretary of Commerce and Trade (1) (Box 24)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (1) (Box 24)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (2) (Box 24)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (3) (Box 24)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (4) (Box 24)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (5) (Box 24)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (6) (Box 25)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (7) (Box 25)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (8) (Box 25)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (9) (Box 25)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (10) (Box 25)
  - 1999
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (9) (Box 26)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (10) (Box 26)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (11) (Box 26)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (12) (Box 26)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (13) (Box 26)
    - Courter, J. Carlton, III (14) (Box 26)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (1) (Box 26)
    - Blankenship, Donald G. (2) (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous - Commissioner's Office (Box 26)
    - Memos to the SMT (Box 27)
    - Dickinson, William P. (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous - Agrib. Development Serv. (Box 27)
    - Kapelewski, Joe (Box 27)
    - Jackson, Karen E. (Box 27)
    - Smith, Harriet (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous - Human Resources Office (Box 27)
    - Seward, Roy E. (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous - Policy, Planning and Research (Box 27)
    - Pugh, Sarah (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous - Ag. Stewardship (Box 27)
    - Lidholm, Elaine J. (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous - Communication and Media Relations (Box 27)
    - Adams, Sandy (Box 27)
    - Layne, Ronald K. (Box 27)
    - 1999 Drought Disaster (Box 27)
    - EEO Plan (Box 27)
    - Pesticide Regulations (Box 27)
    - Agency Regulatory Actions, 1997-1998 (Box 27)
    - Regulations (Box 27)
    - 2000-2002 Biennium Legislative Initiatives (Box 27)
    - 2000-2002 Biennium Strategic Plan and Budget Development (Box 27)
    - FY 2000 Activity-Based Budget (Box 27)
    - 1999 Strategic Planning Session, 26 August (Box 27)
    - CDCI/Y2K Initiative (Box 27)
    - Tobacco Settlement Issue (Box 27)
    - Tobacco (Box 27)
    - Virginia Pork Conference, 21 January 1999 (Box 28)
    - Virginia State Dairymen's Association Meeting, 28 January 1999 (Box 28)
    - Virginia Winegrowers Advisory Board Meeting, 26 January 1999 (Box 28)
    - Virginia Pesticide Control Board Meeting, 14 January 1999 (Box 28)
    - Briefing, 8 January 1999 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting, 10 November 1999 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting, 24 June 1999 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting, 18 May 1999 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting,18 March 1999 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting, 21 October 1998 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting, 2 July 1998 (Box 28)
    - Agricultural Leadership Group Meeting, 9 April 1998 (Box 28)
    - Virginia Poultry Industry - Nutrient Management Issues (Box 28)
    - Tobacco Settlement (Box 28)